

### SAMUEL FERNANDO PANJAITAN, S.KOM.

Padangsidimpuan, 25 May 1999 23 years old – Single – Christian Height 180 cm; Weight 55 kg



samuelfrnando@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/samuelfp

Inspeksi Pam Street No. 6, West Cakung, East Jakarta

# **Work Experiences**

#### **IT Network Engineer**

Mastersystem Infotama, PT | 21 November 2022 - Present

- Handle implementation, monitor, and maintenance project related with Cisco Networking Product (Routing, Switching, and Data Center Technology). Analyze, Investigate if there is an error in the network.
- Design and implement new network solutions or improve existing networks (include design documentation and migration plan).

### IT Business Analyst & IT Support Technician

Uniair Indotama Cargo, PT. | 16 November 2021 – 18 November 2022

- Worked closely with product owners, UI/UX designer and Developers to ensure that our products/ projects (WMS, AICE, SEB) are developed in accordance with the company's roadmap.
- Analyzed systems and mapped business processes to identify gaps and potential for improvements.
- Worked to fully understand the customer data and ensured that the data was utilized to make advantageous changes.
- Manage Master Data and presenting precise and structured reports.
- Provided complete IT technical support services and assisted global management teams to ensure efficient business processes.
- Conduct Proof of Concept (POC) on Access Point vendors (ARUBA, UBIQUITI, SUNDRAY, RUCKUS) to be used at Uniair PLB.
- Assembling Mikrotik networks and data cables, setup using Winbox.
- Update the operating system or applications regularly, Perform data Backup, Repairing damaged user computers and other hardwares.

#### **IT Quality Assurance**

Store2Go | 16 February 2022 - 16 April 2022

- Test the product (Store2Go App) and identify any bugs or errors.
- Create required documents, drafts, with standard QA procedure.
- Ensure that the products and applications designed are of good quality.

## **Licenses and Certifications**

- EF SET English Certificate 82/100 (C2 Proficient) (29 December 2021).
- Dicoding: Building a Mobile Backend Using Kotlin (17 September 2020).
- RH 124: Red Hat Enterprise Linux System Administration I (16 January 2020).
- Alcatel-Lucent Enterprise Geek Battle Scholarship 2019 Basic Programming (18 November 2019).

# **Summary**

I am a Bachelor of Computer: Informatics Engineering. I am equipped with Software Programming as well as IT Networking education. My most recent experience is working as an IT Network Engineer. Previously, I also had experience as an IT Business Analyst, IT Support Technician, and IT Quality Assurance. This makes me more trained to do multitasking in the IT field.

### **Education**

BACHELOR IN COMPUTER: INFORMATICS ENGINEERING - STMIK MIKROSKIL MEDAN (11 September 2017 - 25 July 2021). GPA 3.47 / 4.00

#### **Achievement**

The 3rd Rank in Competition Information Technology Mobile at STMIK Mikroskil Medan (11 January 2020).

# **Research Experience**

**MEDANHUB**: Mobile-Based Information Retrieval System Implementation on Society Reports Application in Medan City with Elasticsearch (13 August 2020 - 25 July 2021).

### **Hard Skills**

- Administration (Microsoft Office).
- UI & UML Design (Figma, Adobe XD, Visio, Lucidchart).
- IT Networking (Cisco Packet Tracer, Wireshark, Mikrotik Winbox).
- Data Analysis (Postman, ELK).
- Web Design (HTML, CSS, JS).
- Programming (C#, Python, Kotlin).

